Kaio Fellipe

DevOps

SRE

Platform Engineer

Contacts

LinkedIn: kaio-fellipe

■ GitHub: kaio6fellipe

Professional Profile

8 years of experience in systems analysis and technology, working in Management, Architecture, DevOps, Infrastructure (On-premise and Cloud), Security, and IT Services. Experience in Architecture and Development projects for Distributed Systems, Business Intelligence, CRM, BPM, ERP implementation, ITIL, Office 365, and Infrastructure/Security standardization, following industry best practices. Experience in a national company in the Agribusiness sector, the largest fashion tech in Latin America, and the largest data analytics and artificial intelligence company for business in Latin America. Currently studying daily about DevOps, Platform Engineering, and Infrastructure as Code for the development of personal and professional projects.

Skill Summary	Level
DevOps	Advanced
Terraform	Advanced
GCP	Advanced
AWS	Intermediate
Kubernetes	Advanced
Microservices	Advanced
Docker	Intermediate
Ansible	Advanced
GitOps	Advanced
Observability	Advanced
Linux	Advanced
GitHub	Advanced

Skill Summary	Level
GitLab	Advanced
CI/CD	Advanced
Cybersecurity	Advanced
Python	Advanced
Project Management	Intermediate
Infrastructure Management	Advanced
Firewalls	Advanced
REST API	Intermediate
Windows Servers	Intermediate
Virtualization	Intermediate
SQL	Advanced
ETL Process	Intermediate
Business Intelligence	Advanced

Languages

Portuguese: NativeEnglish: Advanced

Experience

Neoway (1 year and 6 months +)

• Senior DevOps/Cloud Engineer (Sep. 2022 - Present)

As a DevOps/Cloud Engineer at the largest data analytics and artificial intelligence company for business in Latin America, within the Engineering Productivity team, I deal daily with challenges to increasingly reduce the cognitive load of complex processes for all engineering, focusing on the platformization of internal services.

- GCP
- CI/CD
- GitOps
- Terraform
- Ansible
- Kubernetes
- Docker
- Observability
- GitLab

Dafiti Group (8 months)

SysAdmin (Feb. 2022 - Sep. 2022)

As a SysAdmin at the largest fashion tech in Latin America, I got to know the DevOps culture applied on a large scale, in addition to server and EKS cluster administration I participated in continuous improvement initiatives of Observability and incident handling of eCommerce.

- AWS
- Observability
- ELK Stack
- Instana
- Grafana
- Zabbix
- Kubernetes
- Puppet
- ArgoCD

Safra Rica (5 years and 6 months)

• IT Analyst (Jul. 2019 - Feb. 2022)

As an IT Analyst, I was able to lead and participate in some projects such as: standardization of the entire infrastructure of all our branches, implementation of the BPM methodology in the accounting and commercial area, implementation of the virtualized server infrastructure, and the implementation of a data warehouse created by my team.

- Team Leader (Manager)
- Database Management
- SQL Developer
- IT Project Leader
- BPM Leader
- Network Management
- Windows and Linux Server Management
- Local Systems Management
- Other administrative activities...
- IT Technician (Oct. 2017 Jun. 2019)

As an IT Technician, I was able to lead some projects such as: data center infrastructure readjustment, ERP migration, BI structuring, CRM software implementation, among others.

- Development of dashboards for analysis using SQL
- Database Administration
- Firewall Administration
- N2 and N3 Support
- Network Administration
- Local Systems Administration
- Windows Server Administration
- Other administrative activities...

• Intern (Aug. 2016 - Sep. 2017)

As an intern, I managed to implement the first firewall used in the company, deploying a proxy and an IDS/IPS together, a significant gain in connection quality and security was noted.

- Computer Maintenance
- Firewall Configuration and Maintenance
- N1 and N2 Support
- Network Maintenance
- Requirements Analysis for Process Improvements
- Local Systems Administration
- Windows Server Maintenance
- Other administrative activities...

Educational Background

IGTI (2019 - 2020)

• MBA in IT Management

Senac (2018 - 2020)

• Postgraduate in Information Security

Unifafibe (2013 - 2017)

• Bachelor's Degree in Information Systems

Certificates

DevOps Training (2022)

- Track from Alura covering the following topics:
 - Terraform
 - Ansible
 - Vagrant
 - Observability
 - CI/CD
 - Kubernetes
 - Docker

GitOps at Scale (2022)

Codefresh

GitOps Fundamentals (2022)

• Codefresh

Python Certificate (2022)

HackerRank

SQL (Advanced) Certificate (2022)

• HackerRank

CSFPC (2021)

• Cyber Security Foundation Professional Certificate by CertiProf

SFPC (2020)

• Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate by CertiProf

Network Security Analysis using Wireshark, Snort and SO (2019)

Udemy

Ethical Hacking Fundamentals (2017)

• Udemy

Snort Intrusion Detection, Rule Writing, and PCAP Analysis (2017)

Udemy

pfSense: Complete Firewall Solution (2017)

• Udemy